http://www.themajesticline.co.uk/cookies-privacy/

Book Now Contact Us +44(0)1369 707951View Our Cruise Calendar & Book HomeCruisesSingle Availability3 - Night Cruises6 - Night Cruises10 - Night CruisesSpecial OffersCruising AreaThe Clyde and the Southern HebridesMullSkyeCoast to CoastNorth West CoastOuter HebridesOrkneyWildlife of the HebridesLandscape - the West of Scotland and the HebridesBooking InformationTravelAccommodation ObanAccommodation InvernessAccommodation DunoonCruising TipsFAQsVesselsMV Glen MassanMV Glen TarsanMV Glen EtiveMV Glen ShielGoing AshoreAbout UsHistoryOur PhilosophyOur StaffHospitalityLife on boardFood and DrinkLocal producePrivate CharterPrivate Cruise Charter PricesPrivate Cruise Charter Guest ReviewsWedding Private Cruise CharterPrivate Cruise Charter Enquiry FormReviewsAdd Your ReviewAwards and CommendationsGalleryVideosGuest Photo Competition Winners 2019Guest Photos 2019 SeasonCrew Images 2019 SeasonGuest Photos 2018 SeasonCrew Images 2018 SeasonGourmet Food Aboard Our CruisesGuest Photos 2017 SeasonCrew Images 2017 SeasonGalleryNewsPrivacy PolicyThe Majestic Line Privacy Policy1. INTRODUCTIONThe Majestic Line ("TML") takes your privacy and security seriously. Our privacy policy provides you with details of how we collect and process your personal data.By providing us with your data you warrant to us that you are over 13 years of age.We have appointed a Data Protection Officer who is in charge of privacy related matters for us. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact the Data Protection Officer using the details set out below.
Contact DetailsThe Majestic Line (Scotland) LimitedHoly Loch MarinaSandbankDunoonArgyllPA23 8FEData Protection Officer: Mr Mike ThomsEmail: info@themajesticline.co.ukIt is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at info@themajesticline.co.uk.You may unsubscribe at any time from our emails and postal brochure, simply click here2. WHAT DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU, FOR WHAT PURPOSE AND ON WHAT GROUNDS WE PROCESS IT.Personal data means any information capable of identifying an individual. It does not include anonymised data.We may process the following categories of personal data about you.Communication Data that includes any communication that you send to us whether that be through the brochure request form on our website, through email, social media messaging, social media posting or any other communication that you send us. We process this data for the purposes of communicating with you, for record keeping and for the establishment, pursuance or defence of legal claims. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to reply to communications sent to us, to keep records and to establish, pursue or defend legal claims.Customer Data that includes data relating to any enquiry or booking of a cruise with The Majestic Line such as your name, title, postal address, email address, telephone number, purchase details and card details. Our lawful grounds for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps at your request to enter such a contract.User Data that includes data about how you use our website and online services together with any data you post for publication on our website or through other online services. We process this data to operate our website and ensure relevant content is provided by you, to ensure the security of our website, to maintain back-ups of our website and/or databases and to enable publication and administration of our website, other online services and business. Our lawful grounds for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to enable us to properly administer our website and our business.Technical data that includes data about your use of our website and online services such as your IP address, your login data, details about your browser, length of visit to pages on our website, page views and navigation paths, details about the number of times you use our website, time zone settings and other technology on the devices you use to access our website. The source of this data is from our analytics tracking system. We process this data to analyse your sue of our website and other online services, to administer and protect our business and website, to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and to understand the effectiveness of our advertising. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to enable us to properly administer our website and our business and to grow our business and to decide on marketing strategy.Marketing Data that includes data about your preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communication preferences. We process this data to enable you to receive our newsletters and brochures, to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of this advertising. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to study how clients enjoy our cruises, to develop our services, to grow our business and to decide our marketing strategy.We may use Customer Data, User Data, Technical Data and Marketing Data to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you (including Facebook adverts or other display advertisements) to measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve you. Our lawful ground for processing is legitimate interests which is to grow our business. We may also use such data to send other marketing communications to you. Our lawful ground for this processing is either consent or legitimate interests (namely to grow our business)Sensitive DataWe need to collect the following sensitive data about you in order to provide you with the very best experience on your cruise. We collect data about your health only when it may impact your enjoyment of your cruise with us. We collect dietary requirements to allow our chefs to provide meals to your specific dietary requirements. The Majestic Line will only use your personal information to administer your account.3. MARKETING COMMUNICATIONSOur lawful ground of processing your personal data to send you marketing communications is either your consent or our legitimate interests.Under the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations, we may send you marketing communications from us if (i) you made a purchase or asked for information from us about our services (ii) you agreed to receive marketing communications and in each case you have not opted out of receiving such communications since. Under these regulations, if you are a limited company, we may send you marketing emails without your consent. However you can still opt out of receiving marketing emails from us at any time.If you opt out of receiving marketing communications this opt-out does not apply to personal data provided as a result of other transactions, such as booking a cruise.4. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below:Service providers who provide IT and system administration services.Professional advisors including solicitors, bankers, auditors and insurersGovernment bodies that require us to report processing activitiesTravel Trust Association, who provide financial protection for your monies paid to us for your cruiseWorldpay, who process your payment for your cruiseEmail marketing service providersWe require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.Sharing DataWe will never sell your personal data.6. SECURITYWe have put in place security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used, altered, disclosed, or accessed without authorization. We also allow access to your personal data only to those employees who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they must keep it confidential.We have procedures in place to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach if we are legally require to.7. DATA RETENTIONWe will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements.When deciding what the correct time is to keep the data for we look at its amount, nature and sensitivity, potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure, the processing purposes, if these can be achieved by other means and legal requirements.For tax purposes the law requires us to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they stop being customers.In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data for research or statistical purposes in which case wemay use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.8. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTSUnder data protection laws you have rights in relation to your personal data that include the right to request access, correction, erasure, restriction, transfer, to object to processing, to portability of data and (where lawful ground of processing is consent) to withdraw consent.You can see more about these rights at:https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email us at info@themajesticline.co.ukYou will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive or refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that your personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.We will respond to all legitimate requests within one month.If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk).We should be grateful if you would contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you. Contact us by emai: info@themajesticline.co.uk or telephone: 01369 7079519. THIRD PARTY LINKSThis website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.10. COOKIESUse of cookies by The Majestic LineCookieNamePurposeGoogleAnalytics_utma
_utmb
_utmc
_utmzThese cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.Read Google's overview of privacy and safeguarding data Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. The table below explains the cookies we use and why.Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org.To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.First class in every respect. The crew were consistently friendly, efficient & attentive whether their tasks involved operating the tender, serving meals, tending bar, or many other duties. Meals were outstanding. Highlights - Wonderful scenery, compatible travel companions, efficient crew, outstanding meals, and the fulfilment of one particular Bucket List item, the opportunity to get up close & personal with puffins.— Mike & Elizabeth Cooper: Jun 2019 - Read Full Review
18 Highland Avenue
Sandbank
Dunoon
Argyll
PA23 8PBFollow UsOur AwardsOur Partners
